{
    "id": "63dfc91a26404baba74b8c704d3671c0",
    "title": "Indirect Speech Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I told him respectfully that that ................................... the way to be happy and rich.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The teacher asked James ..................................... his lesson.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "that he should learn",
                "to learn",
                "learning"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Calling me a rascal, he said that he ...................................... me sent to prison.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "would",
                "will",
                "would have",
                "will have"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "John ........................................ with delight that he was glad to meet his friend there.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "said",
                "told",
                "exclaimed",
                "asked"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The child exclaimed with delight that his mother ......................................",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "came",
                "has come",
                "had come"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The captain congratulated his teammates, saying that they ..................................... well.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "did",
                "have done",
                "had done"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The child cried with joy ................................... it was his doll.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "what",
                "if"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The police inspector ordered that no one ...................................... the room.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will leave",
                "should leave",
                "shall leave"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The doctor advised the patient ......................................",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "that he not smoke",
                "not to smoke",
                "no smoking"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Jim requested me ................................... him my pen.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "to lend",
                "that I lent",
                "that to lend"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}